

@

clayton.randall1012@gmail.co m



+82 010-2572-1925



Busan, South Korea



https://github.com/Clayrazzle



https://www.linkedin.com/in/c lay-smith-5090aa57/

EDUCATION

Web Development: Web Development **ZTM Academy**, Online, June 2023

Bachelor of Arts: Cultural Anthropology, Anthropology **University of North Carolina Wilmington**, Wilmington, NC, December 2013

Associate of Arts: Sociology Cape Fear Community College, 2012

CLAY RANDALL SMITH

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Academia has led to the desire of pursuing the pathway of an educational and entrepreneurial career. I've been a foreign language English Instructor in South Korea for 3 years and have gained professional experience in the industry. I'm currently in transition of a career change and am focused on a career in Software and Web Development. This passion for computer technology is motivation to learn and develop new skills that will be valuable for years to come.

SKILLS

- Innovative Teaching Methods
- · Lesson Planning
- Educational Programs Promotion
- · Web Applications
- Web Design

- JavaScript
- Databases: Oracle, SQL Server, MongoDB
- HTML
- Performance Improvement

WORK HISTORY

April 2022 - Current

TalkTalkHi School - Native English Teacher

- Managed classroom scheduling and activities in accordance with school curriculum
- Graded and Evaluated students academic progress and report cards with daily reports, homework and classroom participation
- Recorded student activities in class with group exercises to upload to the local school website with videos for parents to see progress of students
- Routinely formulated student curriculum to fit students needs and learning goals
- Taught wide variety of school subjects and ages from kindergarten to Middle School
- Conducted Debate Class to allow students to use their speaking skills to have meaningful conversations about multiple topics
- Advised teaching staff about proper teaching techniques and strategies for creating new classes.

March 2021 - March 2022

Andover School - Native English Teacher

- Encouraged group discussions and tasks based around sentence and grammar development to increase students proficiency
- Prepared learning materials every day prior to each class based on varying age group and level of English learning

- Utilized in-class activities to facilitate high levels of student engagement and participation in course content
- Established creative improvements on set curriculum to improve students' reception to lessons
- Re-created sample lessons with co-teachers and other faculty for peer review and assessment suggestions
- Presented seminars of new teaching materials to parents of students using video of in-class instruction
- Administered level-up testing to students and created evaluation reports for parent review

February 2020 - February 2021

Feinschule Language School - Native English Teacher

- · Worked with students individually to address areas of concern
- Created exciting lessons on course material to educate and engage students in classroom
- Fostered positive, student-centered learning environments by incorporating gentle discipline and classroom discussions
- Taught English classes to students of various levels from ages 7 to 12
- Evaluated student performance through tests, exams and projects.

May 2017 - October 2018

LONG POND LANDSCAPES - LANDSCAPE ARCHITECT TECHNICIAN

- · Maintained properties of high level accounts
- Willing trainer of new employees to progressively succeed
- Worked closely with residential and commercial clients to create landscaping designs that met individual needs and remained within project budget
- Met with clients at follow-up appointments to discuss level of satisfaction with finished project
- Advised clients in materials selection and provided information on which products would be best options.

January 2016 - May 2018

ASPEN SKIING COMPANY LLC - Lead Foreman

- Assist passengers in safe loading and unloading of lifts, while providing excellent customer service by interacting with guests
- Trained newly hired employees by explaining job responsibilities and overseeing task prioritization
- Developed exceptional attendance record with special attention to punctuality and preparation to work upon arrival
- Resolved conflicts and negotiated agreements between associates in order to reachwin-win solutions to disagreements and clarify misunderstandings.

May 2012 - September 2015

WB Surf Company - Surf Instructor

- Guided clients in safe exercise, taking into account individualized physical limitations
- Developed routines to avoid injuries, maximize effort and facilitate client attainment of personal fitness goals
- Created fitness routines to motivate clients to remain in wellness programs.